:原谅我，大人。我不能。
Father Fox: Forgive me, My Lord. I can't.
俄国主教:你会拒绝召唤?
Russian Bishop: You would refuse the call?
这位修女，尤利娅修女，点名要见你。
This nun, Sister Yulia, has asked for you by name.
我已经通知过你很多次了。
Father Fox: I have given you plenty notice.
应你的要求，我多待了几个月，
Stayed on months longer than I should have, at your request,
我不相信的驱魔仪式
performed exorcisms I don't believe in...
这不是驱魔仪式。
Well, this isn't an exorcism.
这是对神圣事件的证实
This is verification of a divine event
——还有一些翻译。主教，我很抱歉。
- and some translating. - Father Fox: Bishop, I'm sorry.
大人，我救了那个女孩
Father Fox: [in English] My Lord, I saved that girl
是她的家人，不是魔鬼。
from her family, not the devil.
我一直在与精神疾病作斗争。
I was fighting mental illness.
没人能治愈她的时候你治好了她。
You healed her when nobody else could.
你否认吗?
Do you deny that?
我做了所有牧师都该做的事。
I did what all priests are supposed to do.
我给了她我的爱和关注。
I gave her my love and attention.
我让她意识到她的生命是有价值的，
I made her realize that her life had value,
她是上帝的孩子
that she was a child of God.
就在那时，她的病停止了。
That is when her illness stopped.
俄国主教:嗯，也许，
Russian Bishop: Mm. Perhaps,
但尤利娅修女的情况似乎有所不同。
but Sister Yulia's case seems to be different.
当地牧师已经证实了它的真实性。
Local priests have confirmed its authenticity.
我该向前看了。
It's time for me to move on.
做一个好基督徒，不要做一个坏牧师。
To be a good Christian rather than a bad priest.
俄罗斯主教:你真的不应该这么内疚
Russian Bishop: You really shouldn't feel so guilty
感谢你所做的一切。
for what you have done.
祭司的独身主义植根于传统。
Priestly celibacy is rooted in tradition.
不是天主教教义。
Not Catholic dogma.
如果这只是婚外情，而我打算结束这一切，
If it were just an affair and I planned to end things,
这将是不同的。但是…(笑)……我爱这个女人。
it would be different. But... [chuckles] ...I love this woman.
她怀的孩子应该有个真正的父亲。
And the child she's carrying deserves a real father.
毫米。
Mm.
说到爱，
Speaking of love,
这位修女，尤利娅修女，怀了双胞胎。
this nun, Sister Yulia, is pregnant with twins.
她说它是完美无瑕的。
She claims it's immaculate.
她说她的两个未出生的孩子会和她说话，
She says her two unborn kids talk to her,
而且她知道其中一个是好人
and that she knows that one of them is good
一个是邪恶的。
and one is evil.
帮我读一下，好吗?
Take a read, would you, for me?
[叹气]
Father Fox: [sighs]
红衣主教罗素将亲自监督核查工作。
Cardinal Russo will personally oversee the verification.
他是古代语言方面的专家
He's an expert in ancient languages,
就像你一样。
just like you.
为什么梵蒂冈派一个著名学者来?
Why's the Vatican sending a famous scholar?
我是说，像罗素主教那样的人
I mean, someone like Cardinal Russo
有一天会成为教皇。
could be Pope someday.
这说明梵蒂冈对这个案子有多重视。
It shows you how seriously the Vatican is taking this case.
劳拉:[喘着气]看。
Laura: [gasps] Look.
-过来，柏拉图。嘿。嗨。
- Come here, Plato. Hey. - Laura: Hi.
兄弟，过来。
Buddy, come here.
事情进展如何?
How did it go?
和我预料的一样。
Father Fox: As well as expected.
你感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
劳拉:今天早上有点不舒服，但我会没事的。
Laura: A little sick this morning, but I'll be okay.
精神分裂症，受虐待的童年……
Schizophrenia, abusive childhood...
圣灵感孕说。
immaculate conception.
这个女人需要帮助。
[exhales heavily] This woman needs help.
你该走了。
You should go.
你知道她并没有被附身。
You know she's not actually possessed.
劳拉:我知道，但是……
Laura: I know that, but...
这不是一个虔诚的基督徒吗?
isn't this being a good Christian,
而不是一个坏牧师?
rather than a bad priest?
-取笑我?-(笑)我不是。
- Making fun of me? - [laughs] I'm not.
我是说即使你要假扮成牧师
I'm saying that even if you have to pretend to be a priest
帮助这个女人，这才是基督徒。没有?
to help this woman, that's Christian. No?
严格来说，我还是个牧师。
Well, technically, I still am a priest.
但是…我现在有了不同的目标。
But... I have a different purpose now.
我不想因为这件事离开你。
I don't want this to take me away from you.
它不会把我从你身边带走。
It won't take me away from you.
我得去爱沙尼亚工作。
I have to go to Estonia for work.
你可能会比我先回来。
You'll probably be back before I am.
等我回来，我们应该谈谈加拿大的事。
And when I get back, we should talk about Canada.
我觉得埃德蒙顿是个很适合组建家庭的地方。
I think Edmonton would be a great place to raise a family.
告诉主教这是最后一个了，
But tell the bishop it's the last one,
而且你是认真的。
and that you mean it.
斯尼格修女:尊敬的鲁索枢机主教。
Sister Sniger: [in English] His Eminence, Cardinal Russo.
你的卓越。这是我的荣幸。
Your Eminence. It's such an honor.
[in Russian]
我读过你所有的作品。
[in English] I have read all of your work.
你知道我有多受宠若惊吗
I can't tell you how flattered I was
经常被提及
to be referenced so often
在你关于楔形文字的博士论文里。
in your doctoral thesis on the cuneiform alphabet.
你读了我的论文?
You read my thesis?
似乎不管一个人有多老，
It seems no matter how old one gets,
总有东西要学
there's always something to learn
从下一代开始。
from the next generation.
如果你不介意的话，我想给你看点东西。
Now if you don't mind, I'd like to show you something.
红衣主教罗素:什么事，神父?
Cardinal Russo: What is it, Father?
你有疑问吗?
You have doubts?
对不起，主教大人。
Father Fox: I'm sorry, Your Eminence.
外面越冷，我们用的热水就越多，
The colder it gets outside, the more hot water we use,
当热水穿过冷空气时，
and when hot water passes through cold air,
就会发生冷凝。
you get condensation.
除了最初的报告之外，还有什么新进展吗?
Have there been any developments outside the initial report?
尤利娅修女拒绝和任何人说话……
Sister Yulia refuses to talk with anyone...
除了你。
except you.
索尔神父:你知道这是为什么吗?
Father Saul: Do you have any idea why that might be?
啊。狐狸神父，请允许我介绍索尔神父。
Ah. Father Fox, please allow me to introduce Father Saul.
我猜摩尔曼斯克发生的事，或者…
I, uh, suppose what happened in Murmansk, or...
也许是因为俄罗斯的天主教徒太少了。
perhaps because there are so few Catholics in Russia.
我明白了。
I see.
斯尼格修女:[俄语]
Sister Sniger: [in Russian]
[门开了]
[door creaks open]
[in Russian]
尤利娅修女:下午好，父亲。
Sister Yulia: [in English] Good afternoon, Father.
[in Russian]
你会说英语。
[in English] You speak English.
尤利娅修女:是的。
Sister Yulia: Yes.
他们没告诉我。
They didn't tell me that.
你在哪里学的英语?
Where did you learn English?
(重重地呼了口气)我没有。
[exhales heavily] I didn't.
呃。这是我能说英语的唯一原因
Uh. The only reason I'm able to speak English
是为了和你谈谈
is so that I can speak with you.
你为什么不告诉我你为什么要当修女?
Why don't you tell me why you became a nun?
为目的。在第一位。
For purpose. At first.
然后随着时间流逝，
Then as time goes by,
你意识到你是来死的。
you realize that you have come here to die.
但对我来说，上帝说:“不。”
But in my case, God said, "No."
所以他给了我孩子，
And that is why he's given me children,
因为他想让我活下去。
because he wants me to live.
你不认为这些孩子来自上帝。
You don't think that these children are from God.
我认为所有的孩子都来自上帝。
I think all children are from God.
嗯，我想你是对的。
Well, I suppose that you are right.
你为什么要找我?
Why did you ask to speak to me?
尤利娅修女:嗯……
Sister Yulia: Uh...
他们……他们告诉我一些事情。
They... they tell me things.
这些事我无从知晓。
Things I would have no other way of knowing.
他们跟我说了你的事。
And they told me about you.
他们跟你说了我什么?
What did they tell you about me?
他们告诉我你是唯一的一个
They told me you are the only one
这样可以防止坏事发生。
that can keep the bad thing from happening.
你觉得你会出事吗?
You think something bad is gonna happen to you?
尤利娅修女:我今天没有带你来这里，父亲。
Sister Yulia: I didn't bring you here today, Father.
不是教会带你来的。
The Church didn't bring you here.
上帝把你带到这里。
God brought you here.
他们试图阻止他的计划。
They are trying to stop His plan.
[门开了]
[door creaks open]
他们认为自己懂得更多。
They think they know better.
嗯。我们还没说完
Um. We're not finish--
老修女:[俄语]
Old Nun: [in Russian]
我们需要你的帮助。
[in English] We need your help.
嘿，妹妹。我们不是……
Father Fox: Hey, Sister. We're not...
[门开了]
[door creaks open]
[记者在电视上讲话]
[reporter speaking on TV]
[俄语]
Father Fox: [in Russian]
[记者在电视上继续讲话]
[reporter speaking on TV continues]
你想见我，
Father Fox: [in English] You wanted to see me,
-主教阁下?——啊。
- Your Eminence? - Ah.
狐狸爸爸。请进。
Father Fox. Please come in.
-随便喝一杯吧。-我不应该。
- Uh, help yourself to a drink. - Father Fox: I shouldn't.
如你所愿。你认识这种语言吗?
As you wish. Do you recognize this language?
显然是楔形文字，但不是苏美尔文字。
It's cuneiform, obviously, but it's not Sumerian.
它不是阿卡德语。
It's not Akkadian.
这是我从未见过的音节表。
It's a syllabary I've never seen before.
我相信这是一种秘密语言
I believe this to be a secretive language
由琐罗亚斯德教祭司的精英阶层使用。
used by an elite class of Zoroastrian priests.
有点像德鲁伊教失传的语言。
Kind of like the lost language of the druids.
这是原文，
And this is the original text,
从一个人转到另一个人
transferred from person to person
几千年来。
for thousands of years.
这是写在什么材料上的?
Father Fox: What, uh, kind of material is this written on?
红衣主教罗素:还有其他的。看。
Cardinal Russo: There are others. Look.
所有这些都在讲述同样的故事。
All of these are telling the same story.
希伯来语，科普特语，阿拉伯语，阿维斯陀语和阿卡德语。
Hebrew, Coptic, Arabic, Avestan, and Akkadian.
"处女必生双胞胎男孩，
"A virgin will give birth to twin boys,
一善一恶。”
one good, one evil."
在弥赛亚学会爱之前，
"Before the Messiah can learn to love,
反基督者会试图杀死他的兄弟。”
the Antichrist will try and kill his brother."
“他会利用圣人……”
"He will use the holy man... "
两人:“……士兵和父亲。”
Both: "...the soldier, and the father."
我觉得这个词不应该是指"处女"
I don't think this word is supposed to mean "virgin."
我认为这暗示了弥赛亚
I think it implies that the Messiah
会生童贞女，但那是魔鬼吗
will be born a virgin birth, but that the devil
必须通过自由意志进入她体内。
will have to enter her through free will.
她将不得不选择和一个男人做爱。
She'll have to choose to have sex with a man.
当然可以。
Of course.
我怎么没想到呢?
Why didn't I think of that?
[令人不安的音乐播放]
[unsettling music playing]
[令人不安的音乐消逝]
[unsettling music fades]
你觉得这个预言可能是真的。
You think this prophecy might be real.
很有可能。
It's quite possible.
尤利娅姐姐怀了一对双胞胎男孩。
Sister Yulia is carrying twin boys.
这是琐罗亚斯德教的经文，
This is Zoroastrian scripture,
比基督早一千多年。
more than a thousand years before Christ.
其他人和我都相信这个预言
The others and I believe that this prophecy
是和《启示录》一样神圣的启示。
is as divinely inspired as the Book of Revelation.
这不是基督教。
It's not Christian.
我听说你是个多疑的人。
I was told you were a bit of a doubting Thomas.
主教大人，从我今天在这里看到的情况来看…
Your Eminence, from what I've seen here today...
更别提尤利娅修女的精神病史了
not to mention Sister Yulia's history of mental illness,
要是我说了算，她早就进医院了。
if it were up to me, she would already be in a hospital.
她像个孩子一样看待事物。她不理解的幻象。
She saw things as a child. Visions she didn't understand.
她的父母，医生，每个人都在想
Her parents, doctors, everyone thought
她产生了幻觉，所以他们给她用药，
she was hallucinating so they medicated her,
而事实上，我相信她看到了上帝的幻象。
when, in fact, I believe she saw visions from God.
(呼吸颤抖着)
[breathing shakily]
-[时钟滴答声]-[门打开]
- [clock ticking] - [door opens]
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
[低沉的尖叫声回响]
[muffled scream echoes]
你听到了吗?
Did you hear that?
(低沉的哭)
[muffled crying]
谢谢你，狐狸爸爸。你帮了大忙了。
Thank you, Father Fox. You've been most helpful.
你解雇。
You're dismissed.
主教大人。
Father Fox: Your Eminence.
[不祥的音乐]
[foreboding music plays]
-[音乐消失]-[滴水]
- [music fades] - [water dripping]
[老鼠蹦蹦跳跳，吱吱叫]
[rats scampering, squeaking]
(门咯吱声)
[door creaks]
[尖锐的，戏剧性的刺痛]
[sharp, dramatic sting]
(遥远的砰的一声)
[distant thud]
(大声砰)
[loud thud]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
(大声砰)
[loud thud]
[悬疑音乐继续]
[suspenseful music continues]
[时钟滴答作响]
[clock ticking quickly]
-[呼啸的风]-[音乐增强，减弱]
- [wind whooshing] - [music intensifies, fades]
[播放邪恶的音乐]
[sinister music playing]
(低语)的妹妹。
[whispers] Sister.
(大喊)尤利娅修女!
[yelling] Sister Yulia!
妹妹,停!
Sister, stop!
(音乐加剧)
[music intensifies]
住手!
Father Fox: Stop!
妹妹!
Sister!
[邪恶的音乐继续]
[sinister music continues]
(喘息)
[gasps]
(喘气)
[panting]
(尖叫)
[screams]
(急剧喘息声)
[gasps sharply]
(呻吟)
[groaning]
-[突然戏剧性的刺痛]-[喘息]
- [sudden dramatic sting] - [gasps]
(喘着粗气)
[breathing heavily]
罗素枢机主教(低语):大多数人类
Cardinal Russo: [whispering] Most of humanity
将被打入地狱。
will be damned to hell.
索尔神父:在我们引产的时候，它可以让她保持镇静。
Father Saul: It will keep her sedated while we induce labor.
红衣主教罗素:劳动?我以为这是堕胎。
Cardinal Russo: Labor? I thought this was an abortion.
索尔神父:是的。
Father Saul: It is.
但在怀孕后期，必须这样做。
But this late in the pregnancy, this is how it has to be done.
红衣主教罗素:但如果你错了呢?
Cardinal Russo: But what if you're wrong?
我们对教会负责。遵从基督的教诲。
Our duty is to the Church. To the teachings of Christ.
我们不能杀死圣婴。
We cannot kill the Christ child.
我们必须这么做。
We have to.
如果他们出生了，
If they are born,
他们会带来世界末日。
they'll bring about the end of days.
选择是我们的负担，是我们的牺牲。
The choice is our burden, our sacrifice.
那是上帝之声在地球上的使命，主教大人。
That is vox Dei's mission on Earth, Your Eminence.
红衣主教罗素:上帝保佑我们。
Cardinal Russo: God help us.
【脚步声】
[footsteps approaching]
杀死孩子吗?
Killing children?
这就是你被派来做的事?
That's what you've been sent here to do?
当敌基督和弥赛亚
The time will come when the Antichrist and the Messiah
会一起出生。但不是现在。
will be born together. But not now.
你在说什么…
What are you talking abou...
你真的相信这些废话?
You actually believe this nonsense?
她不可能知道她所知道的。
She could not possibly have known what she knows.
-那些事。-什么事?
- Those things. - What things?
红衣主教罗素:她小时候看到的幻象。
Cardinal Russo: Visions she saw when she was a child.
-预言说…——主教阁下，
- The prophecy says... - Your Eminence,
你是圣彼得教堂的红衣主教。
you are a Cardinal of the Church of Saint Peter.
如果你这样做，你会下地狱的。
If you do this, you will damn yourself to hell.
很抱歉，但是上帝之声…
I'm sorry, but vox Dei...
Vox一些吗?神……上帝的声音吗?这是什么意思?
Vox Dei? God... God's Voice? What does that mean?
我们肩负着保护人类的责任。
We are charged with protecting humanity.
[尤利娅修女轻声呻吟]
[Sister Yulia groans softly]
红衣主教罗素:敌基督会回来的……
Cardinal Russo: The Antichrist will return...
当人类离上帝最远的时候。
when mankind is furthest from God.
主教大人，她只是个女孩。
Your Eminence, she's just a girl.
她想要这些孩子。
She wants these children.
(轻声呻吟)
[groans softly]
我做了什么?
[whispers] What have I done?
主教，他们去哪了?
Cardinal, where did they go?
[远处低沉的喋喋不休]
[distant muffled chattering]
(羊叫)
[lamb bleats]
[激烈的音乐播放]
[intense music playing]
[狐狸爸爸挣扎着，咕噜着]
[Father Fox struggling, grunts]
我们得走了，现在!
We have to go, now!
(摔,)
[slamming, clattering]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
红衣主教罗素:系好安全带，否则……
Cardinal Russo: Buckle up before...
不，不，不，不!
No, no, no, no!
[悬疑音乐继续]
[suspenseful music continues]
[悬疑音乐结束]
[suspenseful music concludes]
[汽车发动机启动]
[car engine starts]
[汽车发动机转速]
[car engine revving]
(呼吸严重)
[breathes heavily]
[火车喇叭声]
[train horn honking]
红衣主教罗素:请给我三张去基辅的票。
Cardinal Russo: Three tickets to Kiev, please.
-红衣主教Russo:基辅。基辅。
- [speaks in Russian] - Cardinal Russo: Kiev. Kiev.
[在PA上用俄语宣布]
[announcement in Russian on PA]
(叹息)
[groans]
[英语]劳拉……
[in English] Laura...
我需要你的帮助。
I need your help.
你能帮我……
Can you do me...
(火车鸣笛)
[train honking]
红衣主教罗素:好了。就是这样。
Cardinal Russo: There we go. That's it.
温柔。就是这样。
Gentle. That's it.
你看起来不太好。有什么我能做的吗?
You don't look so good. Is there anything I can do?
(门)
[door opens]
[用俄语讲话]
[speaking in Russian]
[英语]票。
[in English] Ticket.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
这些是给基辅的。你要去塔林。
These are for Kiev. You are headed to Tallinn.
红衣主教罗素:对不起。
Cardinal Russo: I'm sorry.
我们一定是买错了。
We must have bought the wrong ones.
我们不会说俄语。
We don't, uh, speak Russian.
我相信你会在车站付差额。
I trust you to pay the difference at the station.
谢谢你！保佑你。
Thank you. Bless you.
我们休息一下，好吗?
Let's try and get some rest, okay?
好吧?
Okay?
[尤利娅修女痛苦地尖叫]
[Sister Yulia screams in pain]
[in Russian]
修女，你得小声点。
[in English] Sister, you have to keep your voice down.
——请。我很抱歉。-他们来了。
- Please. I'm so sorry. - They are coming now.
红衣主教罗素:我知道该怎么做。
Cardinal Russo: I know what to do.
-[高亢的铃声]-尤利娅修女:[呻吟]
- [high-pitched ringing] - Sister Yulia: [groans]
你得帮她呼吸，好吗?
You need to help her breathe, okay?
她需要吸气和呼气。
She needs to breathe in and out.
-进进出出。好吧?尤利娅修女:[痛苦地呜咽]
- In and out. Okay? - Sister Yulia: [whines in pain]
-[火车隆隆作响]-[呻吟声]
- [train rumbling] - [groans]
(尖叫呼应)
[scream echoing]
[激烈的音乐播放]
[intense music playing]
(尖叫呼应)
[scream echoing]
红衣主教罗素:推!
Cardinal Russo: Push!
-呼吸…和推!——(紧张)
- Breathe... and push! - [straining]
[激烈的音乐继续]
[intense music continues]
红衣主教罗素:它出去了!
Cardinal Russo: It's out!
(紧张)
[straining]
尤利娅修女:他为什么不哭?
Sister Yulia: Why isn't he crying?
(模糊的喃喃自语)
[muttering indistinctly]
(大声哭泣)
[sobbing loudly]
(音乐加剧)
[music intensifies]
(音乐结束)
[music concludes]
(火车)发出轧轧声
[train chugs]
护照。
Passports.
-[喘着气]-对不起。
- [gasps] - I'm sorry.
我们的…我们的行李被偷了，
Our... our luggage was stolen and, uh,
我们得去大使馆。
we need to get to an embassy.
-你有孩子吗?
- Baby: [coos] - You have children with you?
你有证件吗?
Do you have papers?
婴儿(咕咕):
Baby: [cooing]
-[沉重的呼吸]-[高分贝的嗡嗡声]
- [breathing heavily] - [high pitched drone echoing]
婴儿(哭泣):
Baby: [crying]
-护照官员:[咕噜声]-[玻璃嘎吱声]
- Passport official: [grunts] - [glass creaking]
护照官员:[尖叫]
Passport official: [screaming]
(咆哮)
[growling]
[喘气，颤抖地呼吸]
[gasps, breathes shakily]
你会没事的。
You will be okay.
我在你睡觉的时候给你缝针。
I stitch you while you sleep.
孩子活了下来。
The child survived.
尤利娅修女:是的。
Sister Yulia: Yes.
这是一个奇迹。
It was a miracle.
你给他们起名字了吗?
Have you named them?
撒母耳和雅各。
Samuel and Jacob.
- - - - - -雅各。撒母耳。-每一秒
- Jacob. Samuel. - Every second
就是离他的国降临更近了。
is that much closer to the coming of His kingdom.
[笑]
[chuckles]
-[闻一闻]-妹妹尤利娅:[笑]
- [sniffs] - Sister Yulia: [chuckles]
(门)
[door opens]
-我们到了。-[响信号铃]
- We've arrived. - [signal bell ringing]
(模糊聊天)
[indistinct chatter]
[播放不祥的音乐]
[foreboding music playing]
[时钟不祥地滴答作响]
[clock ticking ominously]
尤利娅修女:不是那样的。
Sister Yulia: Not that way.
-[尖锐的尖叫声]-[尖叫回响]
- [high-pitched screech] - [scream echoing]
护照,请。
Passport, please.
我们带孩子来领养。
We bring children for adoption.
看来你今天要让一对夫妇很开心了。
It seems you're going to make a couple very happy today.
是的，我们是。愿上帝保佑你。
Yes, we are. God bless you.
[信号铃声]
[signal bell ringing]
[音乐膨胀，逐渐消失]
[music swells, fades out]
[教堂的钟声]
[church bell tolling]
记者:[在电视上]一次日全食
Reporter: [on TV] A full solar eclipse
预计将于本周晚些时候举行。
is now expected later this week.
科学家已经观察到……
Scientists have observed...
[电视上的记者模糊地继续]
[Reporter on TV continues indistinctly]
(钟铃声)
[bell chimes]
[微弱的高音刺痛]
[faint high-pitched sting]
记者:[通过无线电]科学家已经观察到
Reporter: [over radio] Scientists have observed
全球海洋潮汐的极端变化，
extreme shifts in global ocean tides,
可能是由异常活动引起的
likely brought on by abnormal activity
地核和自转速度
in the Earth's core and rotation speed.
这些海洋变化把月球推离了地球
These oceanic shifts have nudged the moon off
它的预期轨道。
its expected orbit.
这种现象在理论上已被提出
Such a phenomenon has been suggested in theory
但从未在自然界中观察到。
but never observed in nature.
《Kuud Kuulama》作者:Maarja Nuut;Ruun扮演)
["Kuud Kuulama" by Maarja Nuut &amp; Ruun plays]
[“Kuud Kuulama”淡出]
["Kuud Kuulama" fades out]
我祖父晚年住在这里。
My grandfather lived out here in his later years.
我和他关系很好。
He and I were very close.
-你家在油页岩?——是的。
- Your family is in oil shale? - Yes.
我们正在尽可能快地向可再生能源过渡。
We're making the transition to renewables as fast as we can.
到最后他变得很奇怪。
He became very strange toward the end.
但这地方又大又温暖
But this place is big, warm,
应该有你需要的一切。
and should have everything you might need.
让我示范给你看。
Let me show you.
-[电灯开关咔嗒声]-[电噼啪声]
- [light switch clicks] - [electricity crackles]
他并不总是这么古怪。
He wasn't always this eccentric.
他开始为世界末日做准备。
He started prepping for the end of the world.
我想人老了就会这样吧。
I guess that's what happens when you get old.
你的世界真的要终结了。
Your world literally is going to end.
有食物，干货，狩猎用品，应有尽有。
There's food, dried goods, hunting supplies, you name it.
红衣主教罗素:这太迷人了。
Cardinal Russo: This is fascinating.
这是你和你爷爷的合照吗?
Is this supposed to be you and your grandfather?
劳拉:我相信他看到了世界末日的幻象。
Laura: I believe he saw visions of the end times.
这就是他花时间画的东西。
That's what he spent his time painting.
呃。另一件事。
Uh. The other thing.
因为我祖父突然去世了
Because my grandfather died suddenly,
几乎可以肯定，那里还有活陷阱。
there are almost certainly live traps still out there.
但只要你不往北走，
But as long as you don't go off any trail north,
你会没事的。
you will be fine.
我是打猎长大的。
I grew up hunting.
你介意我问一下吗
Do you mind me asking,
你爷爷是怎么去世的?
how did your grandfather pass away?
[播放忧郁的音乐]
[somber music playing]
这是出乎意料的。
It was unexpected.
当然可以。
Of course.
我们应该把它们放下。
We should probably put them down.
我带你们去你们的房间。
Let me show you to your rooms.
“上帝饶恕我吧。”
Father Fox: "God forgive me."
“今生来世，我将继续为你服务。”
"I will continue to serve you in this life and the next."
[轻柔的音乐播放]
[gentle music playing]
尤利娅修女:上帝保佑你，劳拉。
Sister Yulia: God bless you, Laura.
你真是个天使。(笑,抽噎)
You really are an angel. [chuckles, sniffles]
劳拉:[俄语]
Laura: [in Russian]
[继续打电话]
[continues talking on phone]
(门)
[door opens]
尤利娅修女:爸爸……
Sister Yulia: [in English] Father...
让我检查一下你的伤口。
let me check your wound.
好吧。
Okay.
哦，你缝了一针。
Oh, you tore a stitch.
我想你会没事的。
I think you'll be okay.
哦，我可以再来，如果……
Oh, I can come back if...
-不。-哦，不。
- Father Fox: No. - Oh, no.
它很好。我送你上车吧。
It's fine. Let me walk you to your car.
他们能在这里待多久?
How long can they stay here for?
劳拉:只要他们需要。
Laura: As long as they need.
这地方在公司土地上，我不需要它。
This place is on company land and I have no use for it.
谢谢你这么做。
Thank you for doing this.
你提到了加拿大，在那里抚养我们的家庭。
You mentioned Canada, raising our family there.
劳拉:是吗?
Laura: Yeah?
我想一个新的开始
Father Fox: I think a fresh start
对我们有好处。
would be good for us.
真的吗?你是认真的?
Really? You mean it?
我觉得我们回不了圣彼得堡了。
I don't think we can go back to Saint Petersburg.
很抱歉让我们陷入这样的危险。
I'm sorry to put us in danger like this.
不，不，不。不要道歉。
No, no, no, no. Don't apologize.
一个人救了一条生命，就拯救了全世界。
A person who saves one life, saves the world.
婴儿(哭泣):
Baby: [crying]
劳拉:你确定不需要看医生吗?
Laura: Are you sure you don't need to see a doctor?
不，我很好。
No, I'm fine.
修女似乎知道自己在做什么。走了。
Sister seems to know what she's doing. Go.
我爱你。
I love you.
我也爱你。好好休息，好吗?
I love you, too. Get some rest, okay?
——嗯。- Laura:我明天再来。
- Mm-hmm. - Laura: I'll be back tomorrow.
婴儿(哭泣):
Baby: [crying]
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music playing]
婴儿:[继续哭]
Baby: [continues crying]
[婴儿的哭声回响]
[baby's cries echoing]
[紧张的音乐继续]
[tense music continues]
[索尔神父吸了口气]
[Father Saul inhales]
[紧张的音乐逐渐消失]
[tense music fades]
谢谢你。不用谢。
- Father Fox: Thank you. - Sister Yulia: You're welcome.
我想我们在这里会很开心的。
You know, um, I think we will be very happy here.
我从来没有在其他任何地方这么快乐和平静过。
I have never been this happy and this at peace anywhere else.
(柔软的笑)
[soft chuckle]
(小鹿哭)
[fawn crying]
-[小鹿的叫声]-哇，哇
- [fawn crying] - Whoa, whoa.
嘿，嘿，嘿。没关系。没关系。
Hey, hey, hey. It's okay. It's okay.
(小鹿吸食)
[fawn snorting]
[沉郁的音乐]
[pensive music playing]
嘿!那是我们的晚餐。
Hey! That's our dinner.
(小鹿哭)
[fawn cries]
啊。(笑)我们需要肉。
Ah. [laughing] We need the meat.
我们习惯了这种舒适的生活
We get used to the comfort of this life
忘记了这个世界的美丽
and forget the beauty of this world
等于生活在其中所需要的残忍。
is equal to the brutality it takes to live in it.
那个老人，他留下了一张地图。
Oh, the old man, he left a map.
显示陷阱在哪里。他在树上留下了记号。
Shows where the traps are. He left markings on the trees.
有网和弹簧。
There are nets and springs.
泉水是危险的。
The springs are the dangerous ones.
(呼气)我感觉很自由。你不?
[exhales] I feel so free. Don't you?
我有二十年没这么爽过了。[笑]
I haven't felt this good in 20 years. [chuckles]
来了。帮我找到剩下的陷阱。
Come. Help me find the rest of these traps.
我们需要
We're going to need to
如果有一天我们的孩子在这里跑来跑去。
if we're going to have children running around here someday.
(笑)
[laughs]
[不祥的时钟滴答作响]
[ominous clock ticking]
男:[俄语]
Man: [in Russian]
(爱沙尼亚)
[in Estonian]
[英语]我在找劳拉。
[in English] I'm looking for Laura.
(爱沙尼亚)
[in Estonian]
[激烈的音乐播放]
[intense music playing]
尤利娅修女:你的伤口怎么样了?
Sister Yulia: [in English] How's your wound?
哦，很好。
Father Fox: Oh, it's fine.
我们得确保伤口没有感染。
We have to make sure that the wound isn't infected.
来吧。坐下。
Come on. Sit.
好吧。
Okay.
这可能会有点疼。
This might hurt a little.
[轻柔的音乐播放]
[gentle music playing]
尤利娅修女:这不可能。
Sister Yulia: It's impossible.
完全愈合了。
It's completely healed.
(呼吸故障)
[breath hitches]
婴儿(哭泣):
Baby: [wailing]
尤利娅修女:他们这样对我们。
Sister Yulia: They're doing this to us.
[叹气]
Father Fox: [sighing]
尤利娅修女:他们想让我们在一起。
Sister Yulia: They want us to be together.
(打开门)
[door opening]
(门关闭)
[door closing]
有东西闻起来很香。
Something smells good.
-[开门，关门]-[动物嚎叫]
- [door opening, closing] - [animal howling]
红衣主教罗素:完全有道理。
Cardinal Russo: Makes perfect sense.
出生于俄罗斯。上帝保佑你的位置。
Born in Russia. Given your location by God.
看看。在这里。
And look. Here.
看到了吗?这就是你在火车上生孩子的地方。
See? This is where you gave birth on the train.
神圣的大象。
The hallowed elephant.
我想这就是我们现在的处境。
I believe this is where we are now.
你将以牧师的身份死去……
You will die as a priest...
但要重生……作为一对双胞胎的父亲。
but be reborn... as a father of twins.
但这只是其中之一。
But this is just one of many.
这不是预言，但也有可能。
This is not the prophecy, but it's a possibility.
它并不是一成不变的。这取决于我们的决定。
It's not set in stone. It depends what we decide.
你，狐狸爸爸，你，尤利娅修女……
You, Father Fox, you, Sister Yulia...
你自己决定。
what you decide.
婴儿(哭泣):
Babies: [crying]
红衣主教罗素:他们在打架。即使是现在。
Cardinal Russo: They're fighting. Even now.
没有好坏之分，
Neither one is good or bad,
但其中一个是光的管道。
but one is a conduit for the light.
另一个是野兽的通道。
The other, a conduit for the Beast.
-[喘气]-[高音铃声]
- [gasps] - [high-pitched ringing]
婴儿(哭泣):
Baby: [wails]
(楼梯摇摇欲坠)
[stairs creaking]
(充满电)
[electricity crackles]
(呼出)
[exhales]
(模糊窃窃私语)
[indistinct whispering]
(微弱的沙沙声)
[faint rustling]
(充满电)
[electricity crackles]
(呼出)
[exhales]
卡蒂亚:(用外语唱歌)
Katya: [singing in foreign language]
-[悬疑音乐播放]- Katya:[继续唱歌]
- [suspenseful music playing] - Katya: [continues singing]
[继续唱歌，停止]
[continues singing, stops]
(动物的)
[animal howling]
[悬疑音乐淡出]
[suspenseful music fades]
(铃响声)
[bell chiming]
(说教)在他被出卖的时候
Father Fox: [preaching] At the time he was betrayed
心甘情愿地进入他的激情之中。
and entered willingly into his passion.
他拿起面包，感谢上帝，
He took the bread and giving thanks,
就掰开，递给门徒说，
broke it, and gave it to his disciples, saying,
“拿着这个，你们所有需要的人，
"Take this, all of you in need of it,
因为这是我的身体，将要为你们舍了。”
for this is my body which will be given up for you."
同样，晚饭结束后，
In a similar way, when supper was ended,
他接过圣餐杯，再一次表示感谢，
he took the chalice, and, once more giving thanks,
他把它交给门徒，说……
he gave it to his disciples, saying...
“你们都拿着这个，喝了它。”
"Take this, all of you, and drink from it."
"因为这是盛我血的圣杯，
"For this is the chalice of my blood,
永恒的新约之血，
the blood of the new and eternal covenant,
为你和众人倒出来的是什么呢
which will be poured out for you and for many
为叫罪得赦。”
for the forgiveness of sins."
“你要这样行，为的是纪念我。”
"Do this in memory of me."
[庄严的音乐演奏]
[solemn music playing]
(轻声喘息声)
[gasps softly]
[庄严的音乐加强]
[solemn music intensifies]
(呻吟)
[moans]
[双方都深深地呼吸]
[both breathe heavily]
(喘息)
[gasps]
[音乐膨胀，消逝]
[music swells, fades]
(小鸟喳喳叫)
[birds chirping]
婴儿(咕咕地叫):
Baby: [coos]
的梦想。
Dreams.
这是他们与我们交流的方式。
It's how they communicate with us.
就像火车上的男人…我们有着共同的梦想。
Like the men on the train... we share the same dream.
-[播放忧郁的音乐]-宝贝:[咕咕叫]
- [pensive music playing] - Baby: [coos]
我想我们被选中了。
I think we were chosen.
就像马利亚和约瑟。
Like Mary and Joseph.
婴儿(咕咕地叫):
Baby: [coos]
我想我们注定是一家人。
I think we are meant to be a family.
-[敲门声]-[忧郁的音乐结束]
- [knocking] - [pensive music concludes]
(叹息)
[sighs]
-我的天啊。发生了什么事?不是我的。
- Oh, my God. What's happened? - Laura: It's not mine.
工厂里有个混蛋往我身上泼血。
Some asshole at the factory threw blood on me.
[紧张的音乐播放]
[tense music playing]
(犹豫了一下)你是……你确定你没事吗?
[hesitates] Are you... are you sure you're okay?
宝贝，我很好!
Babe, I'm fine!
我很好。
[whispers] I'm fine.
我订了一张去加拿大的机票。
I booked a flight for Canada...
在早晨。我知道这很突然，但是…
in the morning. I know it's sudden, but...
越快越好。
sooner is better for all of us.
-[紧张的音乐结束]-[火焰噼啪作响]
- [tense music concludes] - [flames crackling]
(啜,呼出)
[slurps, exhales]
起初，他们认为是某种病毒或细菌，
At first, they thought it was some kind of virus or bacteria,
但现在，他们说肯定有什么
but now, they're saying there must be something
在空气或水中，当然，
in the air or water, and, of course,
他们责备我，说我有责任。
they're blaming me, saying that I'm responsible.
水有问题吗?
Is there something wrong with the water?
不。多次测试都呈阴性
No. Multiple tests have all come back negative.
我不知道那是什么。
I don't know what it is.
但外面的情况越来越可怕了。
But it's getting scary out there.
我从没见过这样的人。
I've never seen people act like this.
姐姐,你好!你和孩子们还好吗?
Sister, hi! How are you and the babies?
[in Russian]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
哇，他……
[in English] Wow, he...
这些都是我祖父的画。
These are all my grandfather's paintings.
狐狸神父:是的，红衣主教。
Father Fox: Yes, the Cardinal.
如果他感兴趣，阁楼里还有。
There's more in the attic if he's interested.
嗯…[用俄语说]
Um... [speaks in Russian]
[英语]嗯，我会告诉他的。
[in English] Um, I will let him know.
红衣主教在哪里?
Where is the Cardinal?
一定是在打猎。
Must be hunting.
[悬疑音乐继续]
[suspenseful music continues]
-[悬疑音乐淡出]-宝贝:[咕咕]
- [suspenseful music fades] - Baby: [coos]
(叹息)
[sighs]
这是Jacob。
- Baby: [coos] - Sister Yulia: This is Jacob.
劳拉:嗨。
Laura: Hi.
尤利娅修女:这是塞缪尔。
Sister Yulia: And this is Samuel.
在这里。你带他去。
Here. You take him.
(嗡嗡)
[hums]
(库)
[coos]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
劳拉?
Laura?
(轻声咕哝)它们很漂亮。
[grunts softly] They're beautiful.
他们是美丽的。
They're beautiful.
[播放轻音乐]
[soft music playing]
记者:[在广播中]……一场神秘的爆发
Reporter: [on radio] ...as a mysterious outbreak
继续肆虐爱沙尼亚，让专家们感到困惑。
continues to ravage Estonia, leaving experts baffled.
从恶心到精神错乱，
From nausea to psychosis,
不管是什么在扫描到波罗的海
whatever's scanning to the Baltics
这是我们历史上从未见过的。
is like nothing we've seen in all of history.
有人说这是一场怪异的瘟疫，
Some are calling it a freak plague, others,
世界末日。
the end of the world.
许多人认为是疫情爆发的源头
Many believe the outbreak originated
在高斯矿区。
in the mining region of Kose.
一些人将过去的阴谋理论化，
Some theorize a past conspiracy,
涉及几十年前的Kuusik家族
involving the Kuusik family going back decades...
(继续朦胧地)
[continues indistinctly]
[in Russian]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
[英语]奇怪。卡蒂亚应该来的。
[in English] Strange. Katya was supposed to come.
[悬疑音乐加强]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
劳拉:丹尼尔，我这里有些衣服
Laura: Daniel, I have some clothes here
我想尤利娅修女需要。
I think Sister Yulia could use.
你真好。
Father Fox: Very sweet of you.
[悬疑音乐继续]
[suspenseful music continues]
[手机铃声]
[cell phone ringing]
是的。
Yeah.
[in Russian]
[英语]呃……好吧。
[in English] Uh... okay.
[in Russian]
丹尼尔!
Daniel!
丹尼尔?
Daniel?
-[英语]我…我…我…怎么了?
- [in English] I... I... I... - Father Fox: What's the matter?
劳拉:[低声说]有人在外面。
Laura: [whispers] Someone's out there.
你看到什么了?
Father Fox: You saw something?
有人在外面。
[whispers] Someone's out there.
有人在外面吗?
Someone's out here?
宝贝，我不…我没看见任何人。
Babe, I don't... I don't see anyone.
(呻吟)对不起。我不…
[groans] I'm sorry. I don't...
我想我有点多疑了。
I think I'm just getting paranoid.
哦，对不起。(叹息)
Oh, I'm sorry. [groans]
我明白了。
Father Fox: I understand.
劳拉:[深吸一口气]谢谢。
Laura: [breathes deeply] Thank you.
-我爱你。-我更爱你。
- I love you. - I love you more.
(叹息)
[sighs]
安静的声音:杀死孩子，拯救许多人。
Hushed voice: Kill the child and save many.
-我要给你王国。-婴儿:[哭泣]
- I will give you kingdoms. - Baby: [wailing]
安静的声音:我会给你力量。
Hushed voice: I will give you power.
-婴儿:[哭泣]-安静的声音:杀了孩子。
- Babies: [crying] - Hushed voice: Kill the child.
凡你所要的肉，我都给你。
I will give you all the flesh you desire.
杀了孩子，救了很多人。
Kill the child and save many.
你所拥有和失去的一切。
Everything you have had and lost.
-杀了孩子。-[哭泣]
- Kill the child. - [wails]
-[低语重叠]-[不祥的音乐播放]
- [whispers overlap] - [foreboding music playing]
(哭泣)
[wails]
红衣主教罗素:(深深地吸了口气)
Cardinal Russo: [breathes heavily]
(裤子)
[pants]
-[播放紧张的音乐]-[喘气]
- [tense music playing] - [gasps]
(呼出大量)
[exhales heavily]
-[咆哮]-[紧张的音乐褪去]
- [growls] - [tense music fades]
劳拉:嗯。
Laura: Hmm.
我祖父说这是理所当然的
My grandfather said it was supposed to be
我的肖像。
a portrait of me.
来吧。(吻)
Come on. [kisses]
在我们下车之前，我得去趟工厂
I have to stop by the factory before we drop off
剩下的衣服给尤利娅修女。
the rest of the clothes for Sister Yulia.
尤利娅姐姐:(用外语唱)
Sister Yulia: [singing in foreign language]
尤利娅修女:(唱着回声)
Sister Yulia: [singing echoing]
(裤子)
[pants]
小声的声音:杀了这个孩子。
Hushed voice: Kill the child.
杀了孩子，救了很多人。
Kill the child and save many.
[激烈的音乐播放]
[intense music playing]
你为谁服务，你就是谁。
You are what you serve.
[痛苦地尖叫]
[screams in pain]
(退缩)
[winces]
红衣主教罗素:(尖叫)
Cardinal Russo: [screaming]
(呻吟)
[groaning]
(库)
[coos]
(叹息,叹息)
[groans, sighs]
(气喘吁吁,紧张)
[panting, straining]
[远处狼的嚎叫]
[wolves howling in distance]
红衣主教罗素:[哼哼，喘气]
Cardinal Russo: [grunting, panting]
(狼咆哮)
[wolves howling]
-[狼叫]-[喘气，裤子]
- [wolf barking] - [gasps, pants]
(裤子)
[pants]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
-[咕噜声]-[链条叮当声]
- [grunts] - [chain clanging]
小罗素:我们可以让所有的痛苦消失……
Young Russo: We can make all the pain go away...
如果你同意帮我们杀了那孩子。
if you agree to help us kill the child.
你所有的痛苦，所有的恐惧……
All your suffering, all your fear...
(狼咆哮)
[wolves growling]
-[狼叫]-…将会消失。
- [wolf barking] - ...will disappear.
拯救你自己。
Save yourself.
-[吐唾沫]-[咆哮]
- [spits] - [growls]
-[呼气]-[吠叫]
- [exhales] - [barks]
[狼的咆哮，吠叫]
[wolves growling, barking]
上帝啊，可怜可怜我吧。
God, have mercy on me.
有……可怜可怜我吧。
Have... have mercy on me.
-[狼的咆哮]-[咕噜声，呼喊]
- [wolves growl] - [grunts, shouts]
[怪异的音乐播放]
[eerie music playing]
官员1:[爱沙尼亚语]
Officer 1: [in Estonian]
劳拉:
Laura:
官2:
Officer 2:
劳拉:
Laura:
官2:
Officer 2:
示威者1:
Protestor 1:
示威者2:
Protestor 2:
人群:[用爱沙尼亚语喊叫]
Crowd: [shouting in Estonian]
-我们该走了。人群:[继续喊叫]
- [in English] We should go. - Crowd: [continues shouting]
我从小就认识这些人了。
I've known these men since I was a little girl.
我会没事的。我马上就回来。
I'll be fine. I'll be right back.
在这儿等着。在这儿等着。
Wait here. Wait here.
(爱沙尼亚)
[in Estonian]
人群:
Crowd:
人群:[继续叫喊]
Crowd: [continues yelling]
[不祥的音乐播放]
[ominous music playing]
别跟他们讲道理了!
[in English] Stop trying to reason with them!
-[说爱沙尼亚语]-[模糊的喧闹声]
- [speaks Estonian] - [indistinct clamor]
示威者3:
Protestor 3:
人群:[争相]
Crowd: [clamoring]
别跟他们讲道理了。
[in English] Stop trying to reason with them.
(枪)
[gunshot]
-[呼喊]-[继续叫嚷]
- [shouts] - [clamoring continues]
[庄严的音乐演奏]
[solemn music playing]
婴儿。
Baby.
你会没事的。
Hey, you're gonna be okay.
[喃喃自语]婴儿。婴儿。
[muttering] The baby. The baby.
宝贝，看着我。嘿。
Baby, look at me. Hey.
(喃喃自语)
[muttering]
(哭泣)
[sobs]
哦，神圣的上帝……(继续朦胧地)
O holy hosts above... [continues indistinctly]
[庄严的音乐加强]
[solemn music intensifies]
现在让圣灵的火焰降下来
Let the fire of the Holy Spirit now descend
使这人被唤醒
that this being might be awakened
到地球生命之外的世界
to the world beyond the life of Earth.
(祈祷朦胧地)
[praying indistinctly]
(祈祷回声)
[prayer echoes]
(哭泣)
[sobs]
-[抽泣]
- Baby: [wails] - Father Fox: [sobbing]
男:[含糊地说]
Man: [speaking indistinctly]
(深深吸入)
[inhales deeply]
(钥匙紧张)
[keys jangling]
[播放悬疑音乐]
[suspenseful music playing]
Russo !
Russo!
红衣主教!
Cardinal!
Russo !
Russo!
你在哪里，罗素?
Where are you, Russo?
(喘着气,抽泣)
[gasps, sobs]
(狼叫声)
[wolf growls]
嘿!得到!离他远点!嘿!得到!
Hey! Get! Get away from him! Hey! Get!
嘿，离他远点!嘿!(尖叫)
Hey, get away from him! Hey! [screams]
离他远点!(尖叫)
Get away from him! [screams]
嘿…把它。
Hey... take it.
[播放不祥的音乐]
[foreboding music playing]
[远处狼嚎]
[wolf howling in distance]
[深吸气，呼气]
[inhales deeply, exhales]
[怪异的音乐播放]
[eerie music playing]
婴儿(咕咕):
Baby: [cooing]
(祈祷)就像一开始一样，
Father Fox: [praying] As it was in the beginning,
现在是，永远是，没有尽头的世界。阿们。
is now, and ever shall be, world without end. Amen.
婴儿(咕咕):
Baby: [cooing]
(库)
[coos]
悄声说:杀了我的兄弟，我就给你王国。
Hushed voice: Kill my brother, and I will give you kingdoms.
我会让你登上王位。
I will put you on a throne.
杀了我弟弟，你就会被看见。
Kill my brother, and you will be seen.
杀了我弟弟，你就会出名。
Kill my brother, and you will be known.
杀了我弟弟，你就是国王。
Kill my brother, and you will be king.
(哭)
[cries]
(尖叫)
[screams]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
(尖叫)
[screams]
-婴儿:[哭]-[尖叫]
- Baby: [crying] - [screams]
(世行))
[yelps]
- Baby:[哭]- Father Saul:[裤子]
- Baby: [crying] - Father Saul: [pants]
住手!
Father Fox: Stop!
(普通员工)
[grunts]
两个(的):
Both: [grunting]
-我们得杀了那孩子。[窒息]
- We have to kill the child. - Father Fox: [choking]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
索尔神父:(痛苦地尖叫)
Father Saul: [screams in pain]
(枪声)
[gunshots]
-[喘粗气]-[喘粗气]
- [breathes heavily] - [gasps for air]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
[喘气]
[gasps for air]
我们得走了。
We need to leave.
这只是时间问题
It is only a matter of time
在上帝之声找到我们之前
before the rest of vox Dei find us.
[怪异的音乐播放]
[eerie music playing]
[喘粗气]
[breathes heavily, gasps]
(呼吸严重)
[breathes heavily]
看看这个!它是如此的清晰。
Look at this! It's so clear.
这是我们逃出修道院时的样子。
This is us when we escaped from the convent.
我是罗素。他的死亡。
This is Russo. His death.
劳拉。(裤子)还有劳拉的孩子。你的宝宝。
Laura. [pants] And Laura's baby. Your baby.
看看这些画!这是我们的梦想。
Just look at these paintings! This is our dream.
这是我们一家人。
This is us as a family.
(裤子)
[pants]
你还需要什么?你有什么不明白的?
What else do you need? What don't you understand?
[诡异的音乐加强]
[eerie music intensifies]
[笑]
[chuckles]
(笑)
[laughs]
(大幅吸入)
[inhales sharply]
我浪费了我的一生。
I've wasted my entire life.
尤利娅修女:什么?
Sister Yulia: What?
预言是真的。
The prophecy is real.
——是的。——(笑)
- Yes. - [laughs]
尤利娅修女:这就是这一切的意义。
Sister Yulia: This is the point of all this.
还没有决定。魔鬼可能会赢。
It hasn't been decided. The devil could win.
他不是在与神争战。
He is not fighting against God.
-他在和我们作对。-[喘着气]哦，我的上帝。
- He's fighting against us. - [gasps] Oh, my God.
我帮了你什么忙?
What have I helped you do?
[激烈的音乐播放]
[intense music playing]
-[尖锐的铃声]-[呻吟]
- [high-pitched ringing] - Father Fox: [groans]
(咕哝声,呻吟)
[grunts, groans]
(喘息)
[gasps]
[高亢的铃声继续]
[high-pitched ringing continues]
[呻吟]-劳拉:[咯咯笑]
- Father Fox: [groans] - Laura: [chuckling]
(呻吟、尖叫)
[groans, screams]
劳拉:想象一下你的生活会是什么样子
Laura: Imagine what your life would be like
——如果不是他们的话。——(喘息)
- if it weren't for them. - [gasps]
那该多好啊。
How much better it would be.
他们把我从你身边带走。
They took me away from you.
你在为上帝做善事……
You're raising good for God...
但对男人来说是坏事。
but bad for men.
你站在哪一边?
Whose side are you on?
这场战役尚未决出胜负。
This battle has not been decided.
你一个人就能拯救人类。
You can save humanity all by yourself.
你只需要杀了坏人。
You only have to kill the bad one.
现在还不算太晚，亲爱的。
It's not too late for us, my love.
[低沉的声音]杀了这个孩子。
[deep voice] Kill the child.
(正常声音)然后，自杀吧。
[normal voice] Then, kill yourself.
杀了那个孩子。
Kill the child.
杀了…
Kill...
…你自己。
...yourself.
杀了那个孩子。杀了你自己。
Kill the child. Kill yourself.
-[急促地喘息]-[激烈的音乐结束]
- [gasps sharply] - [intense music concludes]
(呼吸严重)
[breathes heavily]
(急剧喘息声)
[gasps sharply]
运行。
Run.
-[敲门]-[播放戏剧音乐]
- [banging on door] - [dramatic music playing]
-[砰砰敲门]-[喘着气]
- [banging on door] - [gasps]
你为什么要锁这扇门?
Father Fox: Why did you lock this door?
-[咕哝]-妹妹尤利娅:[尖叫]
- [grunting] - Sister Yulia: [screaming]
这伤了我的感情。
Father Fox: It hurts my feelings.
(的)
[grunting]
万福玛利亚，充满圣宠。
Hail Mary, full of grace.
主与你同在!
The Lord is with thee!
上帝之母，为我们罪人祈祷吧。
[grunts] Mother of God, pray for us sinners.
(普通员工)
[grunts]
(的)
[grunting]
公鸡的喔喔啼声!
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
别再害怕了!
Fear no more!
(裤子)
[pants]
[戏剧音乐结束]
[dramatic music concludes]
(小鸟喳喳叫)
[birds chirping]
(爱沙尼亚)
[in Estonian]
尤利娅修女:救命!(裤子)
Sister Yulia: [in English] Help! [pants]
-官员:[说爱沙尼亚语]-[用英语]救命!
- Officer: [speaking Estonian] - [in English] Help!
-[播放激烈的音乐]-[喘气]
- [intense music playing] - Father Fox: [panting]
的帮助!他想杀了我们。
Help! He's trying to kill us.
他想杀了我的孩子!
He's trying to kill my children!
-那他就想杀了我!-[哭泣]
- Then he wants to kill me! - [wails]
-你说什么?-[高亢的铃声]
- What did you say? - [high-pitched ringing]
嗯?
Huh?
[高亢的铃声继续]
[high-pitched ringing continues]
(哭)
[cries]
嘿，孩子们，别听她的。
Father Fox: Hey, guys, don't listen to her.
-她就是个疯婆子!-你手里拿的是什么?
- She's just a crazy bitch! - What's that in your hands?
-[呼喊]-[喘息]
- [shouts] - [gasping]
他妈的!啊!
Fuck! Ah!
-[咕噜声]-[尖叫]
- [grunts] - [screams]
[喘粗气，咕哝]
[breathes heavily, grunts]
(普通员工)
[grunts]
(尖叫)
[screams]
(裤子)
[pants]
这是为了你好!
Father Fox: This is for your own good!
我们是上帝在地球上的器皿!
We are God's vessel on Earth!
我只杀坏的那个。我现在知道哪个是哪个了。
I'll only kill the bad one. I know which one is which now.
嘿,嘿。我示范给你看。
Hey, hey. I'll show you.
尤利娅修女:我们注定要保护弥赛亚
Sister Yulia: We are meant to protect the Messiah
从他哥哥那里!
from his brother!
世界不会毁灭的!
Father Fox: The world doesn't have to end!
不要谴责一半的人类，
Don't condemn half of humanity,
因为你不能牺牲一个孩子。
because you can't sacrifice one child.
想想亚伯拉罕和他愿意对以撒做什么。
Think of Abraham and what he was willing to do to Isaac.
塞缪尔，他在利用你!记住那些梦。
Samuel, he is using you! Remember those dreams.
-这是一个警告。-那孩子是魔鬼!
- They were a warning. - That child is the devil!
-[哀号]-如果现在是世界末日
- [wails] - If the world ends now,
大多数人将被打入地狱。
most of humanity will be damned to hell.
你不能独自拯救世界。
You cannot save the world alone.
这需要我们所有人，我们所有人共同努力。
It will take all of us, all of us together to do that.
-我一个人得去。-福克斯…这不是你。
- I alone have to. - Fox... this isn't you.
(啜泣)你一定在里面的某个地方。
[sobs] You must be somewhere in there.
——请。-[雷声隆隆]
- Please. - [thunder rumbling]
-把孩子给我。——请。
- Give me the child. - Please.
把孩子给我。
Give me the child.
——请。-把孩子给我!
- Please. - Give me the fucking child!
上帝创造这个世界是有原因的。
God made the world like this for a reason.
好的和坏的。我们必须拯救他们!
The good and the bad. And we must save both!
-他没有救劳拉。-[雷声隆隆]
- He didn't save Laura. - [thunder roaring]
-[抽泣]-我的孩子怎么办?
- [sobs] - What about my child?
-他没救他——(声称)
- He didn't save him. - [exclaims]
尤利娅修女:(大叫)
Sister Yulia: [yells]
福克斯,停!
Fox, stop!
我想我们被选中了。
I think we were chosen.
就像马利亚和约瑟。
Like Mary and Joseph.
我想我们注定是一家人。
I think we are meant to be a family.
(雷声咆哮)
[thunder roaring]
尤利娅妹妹:狐狸!不!
Sister Yulia: Fox! No!
狐狸!
Fox!
(裤子,哭)
[pants, cries]
[庄严的音乐演奏]
[solemn music playing]
(呼吸颤抖着)
[breathes shakily]
[用俄语祈祷]
[praying in Russian]
(哭泣)
[sobbing]
[用俄语祈祷，抽泣]
[praying in Russian, sobs]
[用俄语祈祷]
[praying in Russian]
[啜泣着，继续用俄语祈祷]
[sobbing, continues praying in Russian]
阿们。
Amen.
(哭泣)
[sobs]
[令人振奋的音乐播放]
[uplifting music playing]
尤利娅修女:上帝选择了成为人类。
Sister Yulia: God has chosen to become man.
和所有的人一样忍受欲望和诱惑。
To suffer the same desires and temptations as all men do.
他也将学会如何热爱真正的苦难。
He too will learn how to love true suffering.
该由我们来引导他。
It is up to us to guide him...
确保他准备好了
and to make sure that he is prepared
去和他的兄弟打架。
to fight his brother.
我们不应该知道原因。
We are not meant to know the why.
爱是前进的唯一道路。
Love is the only way forward.
[庄严的音乐演奏]
[solemn music playing]
(音乐结束)
[music concludes]